

☐ 01523 696 85 99 🖄 gokhandede.ai@gmail.com

Portfolio: gokhandedestudio.com | **Q**|

https://github.com/Gokhan-Dede



https://www.linkedin.com/in/a%C3%B6khan-dede-22129267/

About

Gökhan Dede is a doctoral candidate in the Department of Architecture, Built Environment, and Construction Engineering at Politecnico di Milano. In July 2023, his doctoral studies will be officially completed with a dissertation titled "Machine Learning-Aided Generative Design Methodology for a Mars Habitat." Gökhan received the IBM Data Science Professional Certificate from the IBM Skills Network on Coursera in March 2023, after conducting Al-based research for his doctoral dissertation.

Before obtaining his doctorate in architecture, Gökhan earned a Master of Science in Construction and Project Management from Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University in Istanbul, Turkey, and spent nearly four years working on construction projects of various dimensions. To establish a waste management system for the construction industry, he conducted research to integrate lean construction and Building Information Modeling (BIM) levels.

His passion for innovative technological applications compels him to continuously acquire new knowledge and keep abreast of the newest technologies. He is an architect, designer, and data enthusiast.

Research Grant

2018 - 2022

by Ministry of Turkish National Education for Language and Ph.D. Eduation in Foreign Countries

Education

July 2019 - 2023 **Doctor of Philosophy**

Milan, Italy 🛭

Politecnico di Milano

Architecture, Built Environment, and Construction Engineering

Dissertation: Machine Learning-Aided Generative Design Methodology for a Mars Habitation

Supervisor: Prof. Massimiliano Nastri Co-Supervisor : Prof. Ingrid Maria Paoletti

Feb. Sept. 2018 -2019

English As a Second Language Rice University

Houston, USA 🛭

Istanbul, Turkey 🛭

Oct. Aug. 2016 - 2018

Master of Science

Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University

Construction and Project Management

Dissertation: Lean and BIM based Waste Management

in Construction Industry

Supervisor : Prof. Sema Ergönül

Aua. Sep.

Bachelor's Degree of Architecture | Izmir, Turkey |

2009 - 2014

Izmir Institute of Technology

Certifications

March, 2023

IBM Data Science Professional Certification IBM Skills Network

October, 2022

Deep Learning Bootcamp

Global Al Hub

Septem., 2022

Python Bootcamp

Global Al Hub

July, 2022

Python for Machine Learning

Global Al Hub

February, 2022

Data Analysis with Python

Global Al Hub

Workshops

May. 2021 - 2021

Resilience of Italian Cities: Analysis of the city streets with Al

Cities were visited to take view photos by using a 360-degree camera https://mindearth.ch/2021/05/28/street-view-imagery-vocal-and-ai/

Experience

MindEarth - Short-term Consultancy April July Milan, Italy 2022 - 2022 "Street-view pilot survey" and "Image labelling"

Istanbul Aydın University Istanbul, Turkey Dec. May 2017 - 2018 Design Architect - Educational Building

Feb. Dec. Iki Design Group Istanbul, Turkey

2015 - 2017 Architect in Supervision Team - Emaar Square Project

Maksem Yapı Ticaret A.Ş. Istanbul, Turkey 🖞 Feb 2014 - 2015 Site Architect - Bulvar Istanbul Residential Project

Data Projects

+ CO, Emission Prediction for Vehicles via ANN

Python: TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn

+ Credit Card Customer Segmentation via K-Means Clustering

Python: Scikit-learn, K-Means Clustering, Kernel PCA, Seaborn

+ Medical Insurance Cost Prediction with Ridge Regression

Python: Scikit-learn, Ridge Regression, GridSearchCV, Plotly, Seaborn

+ Falcon 9 First Stage Landing Prediction

Python: Scikit-learn, Logistic Regression, SVM, KNN, Decision Tree

Professional Skills

Coding Skills

Python for ML, SQL, HTML, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, Keras, Seaborn

Online Environments and Management Tools

IBM Watson Studio, GitHub, MS Excel, MS Project

Visualization and Design Skills

Tableau, Plotly Dash, Adobe Photohop, Illustrator, InDesign

3D Modelling & Simulation

Revit, Rhinoceros Grasshopper, AutoCAD, SkecthUp, Lumion3D

Languages

Turkish | Native **English** | Full professional proficiency

Italian | Elementary proficiency

Publications

Dede, Gökhan, Machine Learning-Aided Generative Design Methodology for A Mars Habitation Shell.

(It will be submitted as a research article following the conclusion of Ph.D.)

· Dede, Gökhan, Assessment Of Mars Analog Habitation Plans Using Network Analysis Methodologies

(Submitted to the Journal of Advances in Data Science and Adaptive Analysis – Under Review since October 8).

· Dede, Gökhan (2022), Performance-driven design methodology for habitation shell design in extreme conditions on Mars.

Frontiers of Architectural Research, ISSN 2095-2635. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.foar.2021.10.005.

Extreme Environments of Earth.

· Dede, Gökhan (2021), A Novel Habitation Design Methodology for

Proceedings of The 8th International Conference on Architecture and Built Environment with AWARDs, pages 78-89, S.ARCH 2021, November 2021, ISBN 978-3-9820758-7-7.